<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[ISI Bang Elections 2024-2025]]></title><description><![CDATA[Obsidian digital garden]]></description><link>http://github.com/dylang/node-rss</link><image><url>lib\media\favicon.png</url><title>ISI Bang Elections 2024-2025</title><link/></image><generator>Webpage HTML Export plugin for Obsidian</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 15:37:11 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="lib\rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 15:37:11 GMT</pubDate><ttl>60</ttl><dc:creator/><item><title><![CDATA[Indian Statistical Institute, Bangalore Centre]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br><br>The Students Election Commission of the Indian Statistical Institute, Bangalore Centre will oversee the student council elections for the academic year 2024-2025, scheduled on 28th September 2024<br>For the academic year 2024-2025, the elected committees that constitute the student council are as follows:<br>
<br>
Student Mess Committee

<br>
Hostel Maintenance Committee

<br>
Students' Sports Committee 

<br>
Students Cultural Committee

<br>
Hostel Movie Committee

<br>
Students Gym Committee

<br>
Hostel Library Committee

<br>Additionally, there will be,<br>
<br>
Student Representative

<br>
General Secretary

<br>Each of the above committees will be represented by a head, referred to as the secretary of the respective committee.<br>The roles and responsibilities of these positions are as follows:<br>
<br>
Students Representative: The Student Representative shall be elected for a period of one year. They will mediate between the administration and the students, put forth interests and concerns of the students to the authorities, and follow up on responses from the administration. They are also expected to address any student grievances by bringing their attention to the concerned authorities. If there are any changes in the rules and regulations brought forth by the administration that concerns the students,  it is the Student Representative's responsibility to notify all the students about the same. They must also involve students in taking a decision democratically on the usage of the capital fund. Such a decision must be announced by the Student Representative before using the funds. Finally, it is their duty to appoint the new Students' Election Commission for the remainder of the academic year.

<br>
General Secretary: The General Secretary shall be elected for a period of one year. The General Secretary is responsible for the documentation of purchases, announcements, and notices related to the administration and the committees.

<br>
Students' Mess Committee : The Mess Committee comprises of five members elected for a one year-term. They are responsible for the management and operation of the student mess. Their duties include (and are not limited to) managing mess registrations, collecting and handling mess registration fees, procuring groceries, settling vendor payments, collecting mess bills, selling mess coupons, and calculating and disbursing mess refunds (if applicable). All financial decisions, such as coupon rate, cancellation policies, and special meal arrangements, require commutation with the mess committee members. Any decision regarding changes in the menu must be taken up with the members of the mess committee following discussions with the student community. The mess committee is also responsible for picking interim mess committees for the period of 20 Nov to 31 Dec and 05 May to 18 July. During this period the original mess committee will have no power and the interim mess committee will be bestowed with all the above responsibilities (except picking an interim mess committee). All decisions must promptly be posted on the notice board. 

<br>
Hostel Maintenance Committee: The Maintenance Committee will consist of a total of five members, elected for a period of one year. The members will be collectively responsible for the smooth and systematic usage of various hostel amenities such as washing machines, water purifier, television, etc. Furthermore, they will be responsible for the repairs and replacements of the above, along with electrical appliances in common areas of the hostels (such as lights in the corridors, common bathrooms etc. They will also be responsible for handling the First-Aid kit and helping in medical emergencies by contacting the warden, the drivers or an ambulance as necessary. They will take up these and other infrastructure issues. They are also required to arrange for all forms of assistance in case of any hospitalizations.

<br>
Sports Committer: The Sports Committee will consist of five members, elected for a period of one year. The members of the sports committee shall be responsible for the purchase and systematic usage of sports equipment. They shall also be responsible for conducting various sports activities throughout the year. They shall make use of the fund allocated to them (which may include the capital fund) for conducting sports tournaments and purchasing sports equipment.

<br>
Students' Cultural Committee: The Cultural Committee will consist of five members, elected for a period of one year. They are responsible for the organization of various cultural events on campus including (but not restricted to the fresher's party; the annual cultural events  ('MOBOCRISY' and 'CHAOS'), the design and purchase of ISI merchandise; the annual 'Treasure hunt', and the farewell party. They shall make use of the funds allocated to them (which may include the capital fund) for the organization of the above events.

<br>
Hostel Movie Committee: The Hostel Movie Committee will consist of five members elected for a period of one year. These five committee members will be in charge of screening movies during the holidays and weekends throughout the semesters.

<br>
Students' Gym Committee: The Students Gym Committee will consist of three members elected for a period of one year. These three members will be in charge of maintaining the hostel gym and repairing and replacing gym equipment/facilities.

<br>
Hostel Library Committer: The Hostel Movie Committer will consist of five members elected for a period of one year. Their responsibilities include keeping the library open at least twice a week, managing the circulation of books, buying new books with available funds, cataloguing the books, and so on. One person will exclusively be responsible for maintaining the printer and assisting the students in printing, scanning and photocopying documents

<br>The election to the following posts will be held on 28th September 2024<br>
<br>
Student Representative

<br>
General Secretary

<br>
Student Mess Committee . 

<br>
Hostel Maintenance Committee 

<br>
Students Cultural Committee

<br>
Students Sports Committee

<br>
Hostel Movie Committee 

<br>
Hostel Library Committer

<br>
Students Gym Committee

<br>The Students' Election Commission is the sole authority responsible for the conduct of free and fair elections for the above posts in official capacity.<br><br>
<br>
The Students Representative, the General Secretary and all committee Members will constitute the Student Council

<br>
The members of the Student Council are responsible for making their decisions conspiciously and democratically. The Students' Representative and the General Secretary must be informed of all decisions at all times. Furthermore, all committees must involve the Students Representative and the General Secretary in administrative matters.

<br>
Committees should forward copies of all bills to the General Secretary and provide expenditure and revenue reports to the student council whenever they are requested to do so. This facilitates transparent functioning.

<br>
The distribution of sports and cultural funds will be decided by consultations among the General Secretary and the Student Representative

<br>
If an elected member of the student council wishes to resign, they must do so by writing a petition specifying the same addressed to the Student Representative and the General Secretary.

<br>
In the following instances, upon the recommendation of the respective committee and the Students' Representative, by-elections for a post will be held by the newly appointed Election Commission during the course of the remainder of the academic year.
(a) If a member leaves/completes their course after a period of at least three months after being elected to a post in the Student council.
(b) If a member resigns from a post in the student council after a period of at least three months after being elected to a post in the Student council.

<br><br>
<br>
The Student Council elections for the academic year 2024-2025 will be conducted on 28th September, 2024 (Saturday). The counting of votes will take place thereafter and the results will be announced at 11PM. The Students' Election Commission will inform the student committee on the specifics of the electoral mechanism on the day before the elections.

<br>
All communication regarding the electoral procedure (such as formal declarations of candidacy) must be addressed to the Electoral Commission officially. A candidate can contest for one, and only one post in the student council.

<br>
The Election Commission will release an official list of eligible voters and candidates 5 days prior to the election. Candidates are only allowed to withdraw their name from the election before the publication of the list of candidates, and may do so by informing the Election Commission formally.

<br>
For any committee with a specific number of vacant places, voters will select one member for each place without repetition. The candidate with the highest voting count among the members shall be appointed as secretary of the respective committee, and will be given the corresponding committee's e-mail credentials. Committees with less than 5 members shall have the signee contest for secretary position directly

<br>
The election commission reserves the right to disqualify candidates and debar students from voting if they are deemed guilty of electoral malpractice, which include (and are not limied to) threatening/intimidating students and candidates during the course of the election, defaming candidates/students during the course of campaigning, hindering the Election Commission in its official duties in any manner, and tampering with the ballot.

<br>
In case the elections for a specific post result in a tie, the tied candidates will be asked in negotiate with each other and mutually come to a decision on who should join the committee.

<br>
If an elected member of the student council resigns from their post, completes their course or leaves the institute within a period of three months after being elected, then the candidate with the next highest number of votes will take up the same post.

]]></description><link>README.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">README.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 15:15:24 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>